Register of the Nym Wales papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CHINESE STUDENT MOVEMENT, 1931-1937, 1959 (Boxes 11-14)
  - Manifestos, broadsides, resolutions and appeals, circa 1935-1936 (Boxes 13-14)
    - Peiping People's General Assembly (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - Peiping Student Union (Box-folder 13: 13-14)
      Subsequently known as the Peiping Student's National Liberation Union. Folder 14 contains English translations.
    - Peita University (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Shanghai College of Law (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Shanghai National Salvation Union (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Tientsin Nankai University (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Tokyo Chinese Student National Salvation Group (Box-folder 14: 5)
      See also: Oversize Material, number 6.
    - Tungpei University (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Union of Above Middle School Students, Peiping, Tientsin, and Paoting (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - World Student Association (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Yenching University (Box-folder 14: 9-10)
      Folder 10 contains English translations.
    - Young Students National Salvation Group of North China (Box-folder 14: 11)
- SINO-JAPANESE CONFLICT, 1931-1945 (Boxes 15-16)
  Writings, interviews, broadsides, manifestos, news clippings, and news agency releases concerning Sino-Japanese hostilities during the 1930s and 1940s.
  - Writings, undated
    - "Japan's White Hope: Wang Ching-Wei," typescript drafts with carbon copy (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Collected writings, 1936-1942, undated (Box 15)
    - Chu, Teh, "Guerilla Warfare Against Japan," handwritten translation, 1938 February (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - "Guerilla Activities of the New Fourth Army," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Hogg, George Aylwin, "The Road," carbon copy of typescript, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Interview with General Chang Chun, carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Lee, Hsiao-tung, "The Guerilla Movement in the Resistance Campaign," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Lo, Jui-ching, "The Past and Present Political Activities of the Eighth Route Army," annotated carbon copy of typescript, 1938 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Mao, Tse-tung, "Wei cheng ch'ü ch'ien pai wan ch'ün chung chin ju k'ang jih min ts'ung i chan hsien erh tou cheng," mimeograph, 1937 (Box-folder 15: 8)
      Title translation: "Struggle to Win Over the Masses to Join the Fight of the National United Front Against the Japanese"
    - Matsumuro, General, "Secret Report to the Kwangtung Army," handwritten and carbon copies of typescript, 1936 July (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - "North China Front," communicated by G. M. Hall, carbon copy of typescript, 1943 August 14 (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - "Notes on the China Situation," by I. P. (?), carbon copy of typescript, 1943 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Outline of the political and economic changes in the Sino-Japanese war, typescript, undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - Record of the "Mobilization in the Northwestern Special District for the War of Resistance," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - Report on the Sakai-Takahashi interview, typescript, 1935 May (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - Smedley, Agnes, "China's Northwestern Front," carbon copy of typescript, 1937 October (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - Yung, "The Struggle between Anti-Japanese and Pro-Japanese and Our Attitude toward the Third Plenary Session of Kuomintang," handwritten translation, undated (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Manifestos and broadsides, 1935-1937, undated (Box 15)
    - Chung-hua min tsu chien fang hsing tung wei yüan hui, Peiping shih kung tso t'uan, Fan tui Jih-pen chin kung sui-yüan (National Liberation Committee, Peiping Working Group statement), 1935 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - Hua pei wen hua lao tung che hsieh hui (Association of North China Cultural Workers)
      - Wei shik chü kao kuo jen shu (address to the nation concerning the current situation), 1935 (Box-folder 15: 19)
      - Wei shik chü tsai kao kuo jen (second address to the nation concerning the current situation), 1936 (Box-folder 15: 20)
    - Pei-p'ing ko chieh chiu kuo lien ho hui tui shik chü hsüan yen (Peiping National Salvation Association)
      - Statement concerning the current situation, 1937 (Box-folder 15: 21)
      - Pei-p'ing ko chiek chiu kuo lien ho hui ch'eng li hsüan yen (statement on the founding of the organization, 1937 (Box-folder 15: 22)
        See also: Oversize Material, number 8.
    - Pei-p'ing wen hua chieh chiu kuo hui (Peiping Cultural Workers National Salvation Association)
      - Wei'i erh pa' chi nien hsüan yen (statement commemorating "One Two Eight"), 1936 January 28 (Box-folder 15: 23)
      - Wei fan tui Kuang- t'ien san yüan tse t'ung tien (statement against the Hirota's three principles to China), 1936 (Box-folder 15: 24)
      - Wei "erh ch'iü chi nien kao ch'üan kuo t'ung pao shu (address to the Nation commemorating February 7, 1936) (Box-folder 15: 25)
    - "Shang-hai ko chieh chiu kuo hui kao t'ung pao shu" (Shanghai National Salvation Association address to the nation), circa 1935 (Box-folder 15: 26)
    - "Tung pei lü P'ing Ch'ing nien chiu kuo hui," Wei i erh chiu, i erh i liu chi nien hsüan yen, undated (Box-folder 15: 27)
      Contains a statement by the National Salvation Group of Manchurian Youth in Peiping commemorating January 29th and December 16th 193-, with illustrations.
    - Wu, Han-chen
      - "Chiu kui shih jen t'uan tsu chih kang yao,", 1935 (Box-folder 15: 29)
        Contains an outline of the National Salvation Group.
      - "Chih te chiu wang t'ung chih fang hsiao ti liang chung ching shen" (The Two Kinds of Spirit Worthy of Imitation by the Comrades of National Salvation), 1937 (Box-folder 15: 30)
    - Wu, Han chen and Fang, Yu-yen, "Tzu wo hsi sheng kua ming yün tung" (The Movement of 'Nominal' Self-sacrifice), undated (Box-folder 15: 28)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 15: 31)
      Items in Chinese.
  - Magazine and journal articles, 1931-1945, undated (Boxes 15-16)
    - General, undated (Box-folder 15: 32)
    - Ch'ien-hsien (Frontier), Kuo-min ko-ming chün, Ti shik pa chi t'uan chün, Tsung cheng-chik pu, 1938 February 25 (Box-folder 15: 33)
      From the National Revolutionary Army, 18th Corp, Central Political Bureau.
    - Snow, Edgar, 1931-1945
      - "China's Japanese Allies," Asia, 1939 June (Box-folder 15: 34)
      - "What Can We Expect from China," Saturday Evening Post, undated (Box-folder 15: 35)
      - News clippings, 1931-1945 (Box-folder 16: 1-4)
  - News agency releases and translations, undated (Box-folder 16: 5)
- SIAN INCIDENT, circa 1936-1937, 1960 (Boxes 17-18)
  Correspondence, writings, interviews, news agency releases and dispatches, clippings, and other material related to the kidnapping of Chiang Kai-shek in the so-called Sian (Xi'an) Incident of December 1936. A guide to the material, prepared by Nym Wales, appears at the beginning of the series.
  - "Notes on the Sian Incident, 1936,", 1960 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    Two copies of a mimeograph transcript created by Nym Wales as a guide to the following material. 200 pages each.
  - Correspondence of Nym Wales and Edgar Snow, 1936-1937 (Box 18)
    - Carter, William, 1937 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Gould, Randall, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Grummon, Sandra, 1936 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Hall, Brian, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Herz, Henriette, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - Li, Min, 1936 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Liang, Hubert S., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Ma, Hai-teh (Dr. George Hatem), 1936 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - Ma, L. O., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - MacDonald, Mr. and Mrs., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 10)
    - Mitchell, Mrs., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    - Peake, Cyrus H., 1937 (Box-folder 18: 12)
    - Powell, J. B., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 13)
    - Rock, I. F., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    - Stewart, Maxwell S., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 15)
    - Walsh, Richard J., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 16)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 18: 17)
  - Writings, 1936-1937 (Box 18)
    Arranged by literary form and then, chronologically.
    - Articles and essays, 1936-1937
      - "Conquest by 'Peace and Order'" and "What Will China Do?," typescript drafts, 1936 June (Box-folder 18: 18)
      - "Northeastern Exiles Prepared to 'Fight Back to Old Home,'" carbon copy of typescript, 1936 October 11 (Box-folder 18: 19)
        Draft sent to J. B. Powell of the China Weekly Review.
      - "The Tungpei Army Looks Homeward!," carbon copy of typescript draft and printed copy, 1936 October (Box-folder 18: 20)
      - "The Chinese Puzzle," incomplete typescript draft, 1936 November (Box-folder 18: 21)
      - "Notes on the Sianfu Situation," carbon copy of typescript draft, 1936 December 16 (Box-folder 18: 22)
      - "Nanking's Dilemma," typescript drafts, 1936 December (Box-folder 18: 24)
      - "Democracy for China," typescript draft with carbon copies, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 23)
        Dated December 25, 1936 with a revision on January 4, 1937.
      - "The Crisis in China," typescript drafts, 1937 January 14 (Box-folder 18: 25)
      - "The Present Status of the Chinese Revolution," typescript drafts, 1937 March 9 (Box-folder 18: 27)
        The final page of one typescript contains an edited draft of the first page of Edgar Snow's "The Reds and the Northwest" on the reverse side.
      - "China and Democracy," typescript draft, 1937 March 14 (Box-folder 18: 26)
    - Interviews, 1936-1937
      - Sun, Li, typescript notes, 1936 March 9 (Box-folder 18: 28)
      - Marshal Chang Hsüeh-liang, Northeastern Army Headquarters, Sian, 1936 October 3 (Box-folder 18: 29)
        Includes holograph notes, a news agency release, and news clippings from the London Daily Herald and the North China Star).
      - Colonel Wan Yi of the Tungpei Army, holograph notes and typewritten transcript, 1936 October 5 (Box-folder 18: 30)
      - Wang, dean of the Engineering College at Tungpei University, holograph notes and typewritten transcript, 1936 December 21 (Box-folder 18: 31)
      - James Bertram, holograph notes and typewritten transcript, 1937 February 11 (Box-folder 18: 32)
    - News dispatches sent to the London Daily Herald, 1936 October (Box-folder 18: 33)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 18: 34)
  - Collected writings, 1936-1938 (Box 18)
    Arranged alphabetically by author or title, then by literary form.
    - Bertram, James, 1936-1937
      - Interviews, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 35-37)
        Includes interviews with General Yang Hu-chen on December 30, 1936; Madame Yang Hu-chen on January 12, 1937; and Lei Wei Cheng, manager of the provincial Bank of Shensi, on January 15, 1937. The interviews with General Yang Hu-chen and Madame Yang Hu-chen also include telegrams.
      - News dispatches sent to the London Daily Herald, 1936 December - 1937 January (Box-folder 18: 38)
    - "Chiang Kai-shek's Arrest," carbon copy of typescript, 1937 December (Box-folder 18: 39)
    - "Japan Pussyfoots in China," carbon copy of typescript draft, circa 1937 (Box-folder 18: 40)
    - "Must China Fight Japan?," carbon copy of typescript draft, circa early 1936 (Box-folder 18: 41)
    - "On Leftists," carbon copy of typescript draft, circa 1937 (Box-folder 18: 42)
      Possibly by Liu Shao-ch'i or David Yui.
    - Smedley, Agnes, news dispatches sent from Sian, 1937 (Box-folder 18: 43)
    - Snow, Edgar
      - Articles, undated (Box-folder 18: 44-45)
        Contains typescript drafts of "Comments on Izvestia and Pravda Editorials" and "Izvestia's Comments Objectively Advantageous to Japanese Imperialism."
      - Interviews, 1938 (Box-folder 18: 46-47)
        Contains typewritten transcripts of interviews with Po Ku, delegate of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Hankow, on July 23, 1938 and Miao Feng Shan, political advisor to Marshal Chang, on September 13, 1938 (conducted with Nym Wales). The Shan interview also contains holograph notes.
  - News agency releases, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 48)
    Contains material from Central News, Kuo Min News, People's News, Reuters, Sian News Agency, and Tass. Arranged according to issuing agency.
  - News clippings, English-language Chinese press, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 49)
  - Manifestos, broadsides, reports, appeals and open-letters, 1936-1937 (Box 18)
    - General
      - Ch'üan kuo jen min k'ang ti chiu kuo hui, Wei Chang Hsüeh-liang chi Yang Hu-ch'eng erh chiang chün i ping chien chiang kao ch'üan kuo ko chieh t'ung pao shu, undated (Box-folder 18: 50)
        An address by the National Anti-Japanese and National Salvation Association to the nation concerning General Chang Hsüeh-liang's and General Yang Hu-cheng's armed admonition to Chiang.
      - Hsi-pei ko chieh yung hu Chang Yang liang chiang chün chiu kuo chu chang min chung ta hui, Shih erh yüeh shih liu jih, undated (Box-folder 18: 51)
        Resolution of the general meeting of the Nation's Northwestern Community, held on December 16 in support of General Chang and General Yang's position with regard to the fate of the nation.
      - Chiu kuo shih pao, 1936 December 18 (Box-folder 18: 52)
        A sheet from National Salvation Daily, number 207.
    - All China Federation of National Salvation Unions, undated (Box-folder 18: 53)
    - Chang, Hsüeh-liang and Yang, Hu-chen, undated (Box-folder 18: 54)
    - Chinese Communist Party
      - General, undated (Box-folder 18: 55)
      - Chung-kuo kung ch'an tang, Pei fang chü tui Hsi-an shih pien ho p'ing chieh chüeh hsüan yen, 1936 (Box-folder 18: 56)
        Statement concerning the peaceful settlement of the Sian Incident of 1936 from the northern bureau. See also: Oversize Material, number 9.
    - Federation of National Salvation Associations of the Northeasterners (Peiping), undated (Box-folder 18: 57)
    - Northwestern National Salvation Association
      - General, undated (Box-folder 18: 58)
      - Hsüan ch'üan pu, Wei yung hu Chang Yang liang chiang chün chiu kuo chu chang hsüan yen, undated (Box-folder 18: 59)
        Statement to support the assertion of national salvation by General Chang and General Yang.
      - Hsüan ch'uan pu, üI erh i erhü chi nien hsüan ch'uan ta kang, undated (Box-folder 18: 60)
        Outline of the publicity work in commemoration of "One-two, One-two." See also: Oversize Material, number 10.
      - Kao ko tang ko p'ai shu, undated (Box-folder 18: 61)
        Letter to all parties and factions. See also: Oversize Material, number 11.
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 18: 62)
- CHINESE COMMUNISTS, 1936-1945, 1961 (Boxes 19-23)
  Correspondence, writings, interviews, articles, and news clippings by and about Chinese communists. Most of the material was written and collected by Nym Wales during her stay with Chinese communist leaders in Yenan in 1937. Part of the material found in this series was used to write Wales' Inside Red China, The Chinese Communists: Sketches and Autobiographies of the Old Guard, a reprint of Red Dust, and Women in Modern China. A guide to the material, prepared by Nym Wales, appears at the beginning of the series.
  - "My Yenan Notebooks,", 1961 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    Mimeograph prepared by Nym Wales as a guide to the use of the material found in this series. The appendix contains a nearly complete bibliography of her works, a resume, and selected passages from articles and book reviews about her life and literary works.
  - Correspondence between Nym Wales and Edgar Snow, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    Both Snow and Wales use a variety of pseudonyms to sign and address each other in these letters. Arranged chronologically.
  - Writings, 1937-1939 (Boxes 20-21)
    Arranged by literary form.
    - Diaries and notebooks, 1937-1938
      - Number 1, 1937 June 1-20 (Box-folder 20: 2)
      - Number 2, 1937 May 16-June 15 (Box-folder 20: 3)
      - Number 3, 1937 May 12 (Box-folder 20: 4)
        Includes an autograph of Hsiao K'eh.
      - Number 4, 1937 May 21-25 (Box-folder 20: 5)
      - Number 5, 1937 May 15-17 (Box-folder 20: 6)
      - Number 6, 1937 May 20-26 (Box-folder 20: 7)
      - Number 7A, 1937 August 9 (Box-folder 20: 8)
      - Number 8B, 1937 July 23 (Box-folder 20: 9)
      - Number 9, 1937 August 14-15 (Box-folder 20: 10)
      - Number 10, 1937 June 10-21 (Box-folder 20: 11)
      - Number 11, 1937 June 13-16 (Box-folder 20: 12)
      - Number 12, 1937 June 22-29 (Box-folder 20: 13)
      - Number 13, 1937 July 3-14 (Box-folder 20: 14)
      - Number 14, 1937 June 29 (Box-folder 20: 15)
      - Number 15, 1937 June 1-8 (Box-folder 20: 16)
      - Number 16, 1937 May 4-31 (Box-folder 20: 17)
      - Number 17, 1937 April 21-May 5 (Box-folder 20: 18)
      - Number 18, 1937 April 22-May 28 (Box-folder 21: 1)
        Includes three letters from Nym Wales to Edgar Snow.
      - Number 19, 1937 September 1 (Box-folder 21: 2)
      - Number 20, 1937 May 5-11 (Box-folder 21: 3)
      - Unnumbered, 1937 June 12 (Box-folder 21: 4)
      - Unnumbered, 1937 August (Box-folder 21: 5)
        Contains an interview with Mao Tse-tung on negotiations with the Nanking government and the war with Japan.
      - Unnumbered, 1937 August 18 (Box-folder 21: 6)
        Contains an interview with Tung Pi-wu.
      - Unnumbered, 1937 August 19 (Box-folder 21: 7)
        Contains an interview with Chang Wen-ping.
      - Unnumbered, 1937 September-October (Box-folder 21: 8)
        Includes two letters from Nym Wales to Edgar Snow.
      - Unnumbered, 1937 (Box-folder 21: 11)
      - Unnumbered, 1938 July 27 (Box-folder 21: 10)
      - Unnumbered, 1938 (Box-folder 21: 9)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 21: 12)
    - Books, 1939
      - Inside Red China, carbon copy of typescript draft (Box-folder 21: 13)
        Includes unpublished material.
    - Articles, essays, and compilations, 1937, undated
      - "The Passing of the Chinese Soviets," carbon copy of typescript draft, 1937 August (Box-folder 21: 14)
      - "Who's Who in Communist China," carbon copy of typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 21: 15)
      - Biographical profiles of Chinese communist leaders, typescript and carbon copies of drafts with annotations, undated (Box-folder 21: 16)
      - Lists of Chinese communist leaders according to place of origin, education, and socio-economic background, undated (Box-folder 21: 17)
      - List of Chinese communist political leaders killed or expelled since 1927, undated (Box-folder 21: 18)
      - List of thirty women who took part in the Long March, typescript, undated (Box-folder 21: 19)
    - Interviews, 1937
      - Chou, En-lai, typewritten transcript, 1937 June 22 (Box-folder 21: 20)
        Also includes a revised carbon copy.
      - Mao, Tse-tung, typewritten transcript, 1937 August 13 (Box-folder 21: 21)
      - Wu, Liang P'ing, typewritten transcript, 1937 August 8 (Box-folder 21: 22)
        Transcript was censored by Mao Tse-tung.
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 21: 23)
  - Collected writings, 1934-1944 (Boxes 22-23)
    - Bertram, James, interview with Mao Tse-tung, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, 1937 October 25 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Chen, Tu-shiu, "Money or Service from Everyone!," mimeograph, 1938 January (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Chinese Soviet Republic
      - Chu hsi pei pan shih ch'u (Northwest Office of the Chinese Soviet Republic), 1935-1936, undated (Box-folder 22: 3-11)
        Contains eight documents. Topics include: instructions for grain saving, methods for handling table salt and cloth in order to consolidate finances in the region, problems of summer cultivation and winter harvest, the development of animal husbandry and the protection of ewes, the distribution of land certificates, the organization of labor cooperatives, economic policy, and public finances. See also: Oversize Material, numbers 12-17.
      - Kuo-min ching-chi pu (Ministry of Finance), 1936 (Box-folder 22: 12-13)
        Contains two mimeographs, including a notice concerning recent problems in the work organization of the cooperatives and a notice concerning the transportation of table salt.
      - Shen pei sheng ko hsien lao tung hu chu she chi fu nü hsüeh hsi sheng chan tsu ti tsu shu jen shu ho chung tzu chi mien tzu ti fen p'ei piao, 1936 (Box-folder 22: 14)
        Statistics concerning agricultural cooperative groups in Shenpei province.
      - Shen pai sheng Su yenan teng ch'i hsien jen k'ao tiao ch'a t'ung chi i lan piao, 1936 (Box-folder 22: 15)
        Population statistics from Shenpei province.
      - Ts'ai-cheng pu, Chan-hsing chin-k'u tiao-li, mimeograph, 1936 (Box-folder 22: 16)
        Contains information about treasury regulations.
    - Chou, En-lai, 1938, undated (Box-folder 22: 17-18)
      Contains a mimeograph entitled, "How to Carry on a Protracted War," written in February of 1938 and an undated carbon copy of a typescript entitled, "On the People's Congress."
    - Chu, Teh, Chung-kuo king nung hung chun, Hung chün tsung ssu ling pu ming ling, 1935 November (Box-folder 22: 19)
      A proclamation from the headquarters of the Red Army encouraging Nationalist army personnel to defect. See also: Oversize Material, number 18.
    - Chung-kuo kung ch'an tang (Communist Party of China)
      - Chung yang wei yüan hui, Chung kuo kung ch'an tang chih chung-kuo kuo min tang shu, 1936 August (Box-folder 22: 20)
        A letter from the Central Committee of the Communist Party to the Kuomintang concerning the United Front against Japan. Includes a mimeograph with an English translation attached.
      - Chung yang wei yüan hui, Chung yang kuan yü t'u ti cheng tse ti chih shih, 1936 (Box-folder 22: 21)
        A notice from the Central Committee concerning land policy.
      - Hsi pei chung yang ch'u. Kuan yu chih hsing kai pein fu nung tse lueh chi ko chi kung ch'an tang yu su wei ai ti chih shih, 1936 (Box-folder 22: 22)
        A handwritten notice from the Northwest Bureau of the Communist Party concerning the transportation of rich peasants.
    - Chung-kuo kung nung hung chün, undated (Box-folder 22: 23-24)
      Contains the first page of a manuscript in Chinese (with English translation) titled, "History of the Growth of the Red Army, 193-," which discusses the time period from Wu-Han to Ching Kan Shan. Also included is a handwritten list of battles from the headquarters of the First Chinese Worker and Peasant Red Army in Chinese. See also: Oversize Material, numbers 19 and 20.
    - "Fundamental Problems of the Chinese Revolution," lecture series notes, undated (Box-folder 22: 25)
    - Hearn, Laurence, book review of Edgar Snow's Red Star Over China, typescript, undated (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Hsüeh-feng and Hsiao-p'eng, Lou-shan kuan ch'ien hou, 1935 (Box-folder 23: 2)
      Contains handwritten personal narratives of the events before and after the capture of Loushan pass. Also includes a typescript English translation.
    - Hsiao, Hua, Kuo ch'ü ti wo (I Was), 1936 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      Biography of a Communist Party member. See also: Oversize Material, number 21.
    - I chiu san san Chung-kuo ching chi wei chi ti chien jui hua, 1930s (Box-folder 23: 4)
      Carbon copy of handwritten manuscript which discusses critical economic conditions in China based on a statistical survey by a Communist economist.
    - I chün t'uan wen-fang chan tou, 1934 (Box-folder 23: 5)
      Carbon copy of handwritten manuscript discussing the battle of Wen-fang. Includes a typescript English translation.
    - Lin, Tzu-han, report to the Border Region People's Congress, mimeograph, undated (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Mao, Tse-tung
      - Appeal to Chinese Muslims for support, mimeograph in Arabic, 1936 (Box-folder 23: 7)